前情提要
Previously on Stargate Atlantis...
Ellis上校 欢迎你们首次拜访
非常准时
Colonel Ellis, you made excellent
time on your first voyage here.
复制者们知道地球的位置
而这些飞船
The replicators know the location
of earth, and with these new ships,
可以帮他们到达那里
have the means to get there.
那么 我们要炸毁他们的飞船
So, you're going to blow up their ships.
Oberoth...
我们攻击你们是别无选择的
你们正在建造战舰 他们必须被摧毁
we had to attack you.You were building
warships.They needed to be neutralized.
现在 你们也是一样
And now so do you.
不管我们躲藏在这个星球上
的哪个地方
No matter where we try
to hide on this planet,
复制者的卫星总有办法追踪我们
the replicator satellite
will be able to track us.
我们让城市下沉
We submerge the city.
海水可以减弱光束的强度
为我们争取一些护盾使用时间
The water attenuates the satellite's beam
intensity, buys us some more shield time.
海水没有效果?
The water has no effect?
有效果 只是距离我们设想的太远
It's having an affect, but just
nowhere near what we want it to.
你想让一颗小行星向我们飞来?
这样做明智吗?
You want to bring an asteroid
towards us?Is that wise?
Atlantis 要离开这个星球了
Atlantis is leaving this planet.
- 我们飞得还不够高
- 我们没有足够的能量
We're not flying high enough.We
don't have enough power.
关掉护盾
Lower the shield.
超光速引擎关闭了
The hyperdrive just
shut down.We are lost.
我们迷失了
我们脱离超空间太快了
We dropped out of
hyperspace way too soon.
我不知道我们现在在哪
I have no idea where we are.
她没有反映
而且瞳孔反映迟缓
She's unresponsive and
her pupils are sluggish.
我要你准备手术室
确保我们到的时候扫描器可以用
I need you to prep the O.R.And have
the scanner ready when we get there.
我们这就开始
扫描器正在就位
We're on it.The scanner
is moving into position.
她要不行了
She's crashing.
伙计们快点
我可不想在走廊里抢救
Let's go, guys.I don't
want to do this in the hall.
好了 好了
Here we go, here we go.
城市内的传感器上线了吗?
You got city-wide
sensors back on-line?
谢天谢地 是的
正在缓缓启动
Hopefully, yeah.Slowly
booting up right now.
我们能联系Apollo了吗?
Can we contact the Apollo?
- 还不行
- 为什么?
- Not yet, no.
- Why not?
次空间通信还没有恢复
Because sub-space
communications are down.
别担心 我叫Chuck去解决了
Don't worry, I've got
chuck working on it.
也许你应该亲自解决
Well, maybe you should be working on it.
我还有更重要的事要干
I've got bigger fish to fry.
还有什么能比联系Apollo更重要呢?
What could be more important
than contacting the Apollo?
这不可能!
This can't be right.
怎么了?
What's wrong?
能量!
Power.
我们正在大量地失去能量
We're losing massive amounts of power.
- 把它拔出来就好了
- 不行
- Just pull it out.
- I can't do that.
为什么?
Why not?
等扫描器空出来
我们得让你扫描一下
We have to wait to get
you under the scanner,
要保证把它拔出来
不会给你造成更多伤害
make sure pulling it out's not
going to cause even more damage.
拔-出-来!
Pull...it...out.
好好 我懂 你很强悍
Yeah, yeah, I get it,
you're a tough guy.
如果你要吧的话 请自便...
If you want to pull it out, go
ahead, but I'm not going to--
你疯了吗?!
are you crazy?
数到3 准备
On three, ready?
1 2 3
One, two, three.
清开
Clear.
充电
Charge it.
我觉得问题不在我们这边
I don't think the
problem is on this end.
我不管问题在哪一边
我想知道是什么出了问题
I don't care where the problem is,
I want to know what the problem is.
是线路
It's in the conduits.
看上去...
It looks like...
几个主要的线路都被光束
的冲击波影响到了
several main conduits
were affected by the beam.
那就是我们得...
All right, that means
that we'll need to, uh--
是 是 你应该去...
Yes, yes, yes. You
should get the--
我会的 但是我得先关掉...
Yeah, I will, as soon as
I've shut down all of the--
是的 我也一样
Yes, yes, yes, I will do the same thing.
等一下 这里发生了什么?
Wait, wait, wait, what's going on here?
我每浪费一秒钟
就会消耗掉更多的能量
Every second I waste,
we're draining more power.
相信我 我们做的没错
Just trust me, we're
doing the right thing.
没有效果
No change.
我们试试甘露醇(减小颅内压药物)
静注200cc
Let's start her on mannitol, 200 cc's iv.
Rodney 告诉我发生了什么事
Tell me what's going on, Rodney.
长话短说 有一堆不需要开的系统
现在还开着
Long story short, there are a bunch of
systems on right now that don't need to be,
照目前的情况
它们正在消耗这座城市的"生命"
and given our current situation, they're
draining the life out of the city.
你不能关掉它们吗?
Can you not just shut them off?
等一下...
Yeah, just wait, uh...
也许 可以
Maybe, yeah.
快点...
Come on...
Aw, come on...
时间?
Time?
心脏停跳已经2分钟了
She's been flat for almost two minutes.
求你 Elizabeth 我们这里需要你
Come on, we need you here, Elizabeth.
她的心室纤维恢复颤动了
我们再电击一次
She's going back into v-fib.
Let's hit her again.
清开
Clear.
好了
伙计们 我们来扫描一下
There we go. There we go.
Let's start the scan.
Keller医生?
Dr.Keller?
这可不太好
That's not good.
她的大脑肿胀得很厉害
Her brain is swelling quite seriously.
着解释了瞳孔反应迟缓
That would explain the sluggish pupils.
和其他的问题
Yeah, among other things.
注射30毫克尼莫地平
还有注意一下她的血压
Give her nimodipine, 30 milligrams q four
h, and keep an eye on her blood pressure.
(尼莫地平是钙通道拮抗剂,用于保护脑神经元)
Nothing.
都没用
控制板都失灵了
我没法在这关掉系统
The control grid's all out of whack.
I can't shut the systems down from here.
这座城市在"流血"
We're bleeding out.
我们可以手动关闭系统 不是吗?
We can shut down the
systems manually, right?
我不认为我们有那么多时间
I don't think we have the time.
你连试都不想试一下吗?
You would rather not try?
好了 你们是对的
Okay, you're right, you're right.
Zelanka? 我需要你部署一些小队
Zelenka...we need to deploy some teams.
她没有反映
She's not responding.
我们要失去她了
We're losing her.
我正在派一些人和你们一起
以备需要
I'm sending some of my men with
your guys in case they need help.
预计5分钟内到达 这时间足够吗?
Their eta is under five minutes.Does
that give us enough time?
我不知道
我们剩下的一点点能量快用完了
I don't know.What little power
we had left is almost gone.
如果能撑到晚上就是很幸运的了
We'll be lucky if we can
make it through the night.
星际之门亚特兰蒂斯
第四季 第一集
stargate.atlantis
Season4 Episode01
听着...
Listen...
怎么了?
What?
你在没有询问我的情况下
做了很多决定
You've been making a lot of
decisions without consulting me.
对不起 我这就像在枪口上一样
事情得很快完成
Sorry. We're a little under
the gun here. Things move fast.
我知道 但是Elizabeth现在...
I understand that, but with Elizabeth...
不能领导...
incapacitated.
我讨厌这么说 但是...
I hate to say it, but, uh...
你负责 我知道了...
抱歉
You're in charge.I know, I'm sorry.
凡事通知我一下就好了
Just keep me in the loop.
(一种加拿大的学生参看资料)
好的 我会给你 Cole Notes
Okay. Okay, well, I'll
give you the coles notes.
什么?
The what?
(Cole Notes的美国版)
嗯 那Cliff Notes呢?
Uh, the cliff notes?
你直说不就好了吗?
Why didn't you just say that?
好吧 不管了
Look, never mind.
我们离开Lantia的时候
我们被复制者的卫星击中了
Look, as we were leaving Lantia, we got grazed
by the replicator's satellite beam, right?
光束打中了塔楼的一侧
据我们所知
It impacted the side of the
tower, and from what we can tell,
它对一些能量管线造成了很大的破怀
it wreaked havoc on a
number of power conduits.
那么 改变接线不就行了
So? Re-route the power then.
没这么简单
Yeah, it's not so easy.
你看 ZPM室在这个塔的底部
Look, the ZPM room is
at the base of the tower,
也就是说被击中的管线是主要管线
which means the conduits in and around
where the beam hit are primary conduits.
它们无法被替代
They can't be routed around.
那么城市的部分会没有能量供应?
So parts of the city don't have power?
不是 管线没有挂掉
它们只是损坏了
No, no, no, the conduits weren't
severed, they were damaged.
这个很复杂
但是就把他们想成...
Look, it's complicated,
but imagine them as, uh...
- 漏了的管子 好吗?
- 好吧
- leaky pipes, okay?
- Okay...
那么你抽水进去它们会漏 对吧?
you pump water through
them, they leak, right?
你再讲白痴一点 我就打你了
You dumb this down any more,
and you're going to get hit.
对不起
Sorry.
城市发现不管因为什么原因
Look, the city realizes
that, for whatever reason,
能量没有到达外围平台
power's not making
it to the outer piers,
所以 因为城市无法自己修复泄漏
so instead of repairing the
leaks, which it can't do,
它提升了ZMP输出
这样 即使管子是漏的
it increases the ZPM's output so that even
though the pipes are leaky and we lose power,
也有足够的能量可以到达线路的末端
enough energy makes it
to the end of the line.
- 这么说这很糟糕?
- 没有 这是好事
- And that's bad?
- No, that's good.
如果不这样的话 我们会失去护盾
没有大气 我们就会死了
Well, otherwise, we'd lose the shields.We'd
lose atmosphere.We'd all be dead.
然后?
Okay...
现在有一些不需要的系统开着
Look, there are a number of systems
on right now that don't need to be,
而且它们在要能量
and they're screaming for power.
我们可能正在失去致命的量的能量
Look, we're going to lose juice,
potentially a fatal amount,
但是如果我们可以关闭
那些非必须的系统
no matter what we do, but if we can get
those nonessential systems shut down,
ZPM就可以输出更少的能量
到泄漏的管道里
then the ZPM will need to pump
less power through the leaky pipes,
我们也许可以多活一个多小时
and we'll put off imminent
death for another hour or so.
那么 我们的进度如何?
So then, where are we at?
看 各个小组的进度不错
Well, the teams are making good time.
我们已经关闭了60%的非必要系统
那么...
We've got about 60% of the
nonessential systems shut down, so--
什么? 怎么了?
What? What's happening?
城市的外围建筑正在减压
而且在关闭人工重力
The city's outer buildings are decompressing,
shutting down their artificial gravity.
城市为什么要这么做?
Why would the city do such a thing?
它正在缩小护盾以节约能源
It's going to collapse the shield.
It's trying to save power.
我们有人在那里
We've got guys out there.
Matthews 马上回到塔里来
Matthews, fall back to
the tower immediately.
我们还没有干完 长官
I don't think we're done, Sir.
城市的护盾正在缩小 行动
The city's shield's collapsing. Move.
你们都听到了 快走
You heard the man. Go, go!
他们会来不及的
They're not going to make it.
阻止它 让它停下来
Stop it. Stop it from doing this.
城市认为它无法维持护盾
除非我们让它小一点
The city doesn't think it can maintain
the shield unless we make it smaller.
如果我推迟缩小
护盾可能会整体失效
If we delay its collapse,
it could fail completely.
我不管 超驰控制
I don't care. Override it.
他不让我超驰
It's not letting me.
我们快到了
We're almost there.
我们会失去他们的 Mckay!
We're going to lose those guys, McKay!
你认为我不知道吗?
You think I don't realize that?
人工重力刚刚关闭了!
The gravity just shut down!
生命信号终结
bio signatures terminated
叫其他小队快一点
Tell the other teams to hurry.
我不想让他们在外面多呆一秒钟
I don't want them out there
any longer than they need to be.
你有发现U盘数据率不同步的问题吗?
Hey, are you getting the same data rate
inconsistencies off these flash drives?
Bill? Bill?
Bill?Bill?
哦 对不起
Oh, sorry.
哦 天
Oh, boy.
应该是这该死的失重
It's this damn weightlessness.
也许你应该回地球上去
You know, maybe you
should gate back to earth.
我可以找别人
帮我把空间站运行起来
I can get somebody else to help
me bring the station on-line.
不用 只要我想出办法让重力恢复
就会没事的
No.I'll be fine, as soon as I can figure
out how to get the gravity back on.
你说U盘怎么了?
Uh, what were you saying
about the flash drives?
就是我没次更新软件的时候
这些驱动器...
Yeah, it's just that every time I
update the software, the drives--
飞马系那边的星门启动了
The pegasus gate just activated.
我是Abe Ellis上校
Apollo的指挥官
This is colonel abe ellis,
commander of the Apollo.
中途站 请回话
Midway station, please respond.
Ellis上校 我是Samantha Carter上校
Colonel Ellis, this is
Colonel Samantha Carter.
我在中途站
I am on the midway station.
任务进行的如何?
How did the mission go?
据我们所知
Atlantis成功逃离了复制者的光束
Well, as far as we can tell, atlantis
successfully evaded the replicator's beam
并且进入了超空间
and was able to enter hyperspace.
据你们所知?
From what you can tell?
他们没有到达预定的会和地点
Well, they're not at the
predetermined rendezvous point.
真的?
Really?
他们应该在那迎接你们的
They should have beaten you there.
事实上 你们是怎么拨通的?
Actually, hey, how are you dialing us?
M12-578没有星门 它不在系统内
M12-578 doesn't have a
gate. It's off the grid.
我跳跃到了最近得星门
来看看他们有没有向你们报道
I jumped to the nearest gate to
see if they've checked in with you.
那么 很抱歉 他们没有
Well, I'm sorry to
say that they haven'T.
这可能不是好事
That's probably not good.
是的 不太好
No, probably not.
我马上回头 一小时之内再打给你
如果联系上他们那会提前
I'll head back, dial you again in
an hour, sooner if I hear from them.
- 可以
- Apollo收线
- Sounds good.
- Apollo out.
嗨 你应该在床上
Hey, you should be in bed.
她怎么样?
How's she doing?
她的大脑正在胀大 很严重
Her brain is swelling, drastically,
已经超过了她头部承受的极限
more than her head can handle.
如果不停止的化
他们就得进行减压开颅手术
If it doesn't stop, they're going to have
to perform a decompressive craniectomy.
简单点说 他们切掉一块头骨
Basically, they cut out
a piece of her skull,
然后她的大脑就可以扩展到外面
and the brain is allowed to
expand outside of her head.
有她的消息吗?
Any word on how she's doing?
她还在手术室
还没有什么实质性的消息
She's still in the O.R. No real news yet.
听着 我想我们得把护盾收缩到
塔楼这里来
Listen, I think we should collapse
the shield right to the tower.
那会使我们完全暴露在太空中
That will leave us
completely exposed to space.
是的没错 但是我们的能量太少了
Yes, it will, but our power
is spread so thin right now,
我没有任何多余的能量来解决
I don't have any extra juice to come
up with the solutions to the hundred
这么多可以宣告我们死亡的问题
or so problems that could lead
to our premature demise today.
好吧 联系一下Zelenka
确定所有的小队都到了
All right, check with Zelenka. Make sure
all the science teams are accounted for.
已经搞懂 我们准备好了
Already done, we're ready.
好吧
All right.
做你该做的
Do what you need to do.
OK 开始吧
Okay, here we go.
钙通道抗结剂没有什么效果
The calcium channel blockers
aren't having much effect.
- 颅内压多少?
- 35
What's her intracranial pressure?
我不能让它达到40
I can't let her get to 40.
好吧...
Okay...
准备进行开颅减压手术
Let's prep for a
decompressive craniectomy.
压力下降到29
Pressure down to 29.
幸运的话 我们可以让它降到25
Hopefully, we'll get it under 25.
是的...
Yeah...
好的 两个好消息
all right, two bits of good news.
第一 我计算出了我们的准确位置
One, I've been able to
calculate our exact location.
那就是说我们可以使用星门了?
Does that mean we can use the gate?
很可惜 不行
Sadly, no.
如果要启动星门
我们必须停留在很小的空间范围
To activate the gate, we require that we
stay within a fairly small area of space.
我们现在移动的太快了
We're moving too fast to use it.
我们能用亚光速引擎来减速吗?
Can we use the sub-lights to slow down?
如果它们在工作的话就太好了
Well, it would be great
if they were working,
亚光速引擎和导航系统不能用
but sub-light and navigation are out.
你把这个也算作好消息?
You decided to put this
in the good news category?
至少我们不在是迷失了 不是吗?
Well, at least we're
not lost anymore, right?
第二 我们的星际引擎没有损坏
Number two, there is nothing
wrong with our hyperdrives.
那么我们为什么提早退出了超空间?
Then why did we fall out
of hyperspace prematurely?
因为能量管线损坏
The damaged power conduits.
这么说吧 我们的油箱里有足够的油
只是我们没法让他们到达引擎
We had plenty of gas in the tank, so to
speak, we just couldn't get it to the engine.
我们就失速了
Stalled out.
那么如果修理好管线
我们可以超空间吗?
So if we repair the conduits,
can we jump into hyperspace?
我们就是这么想的
在不降落并关闭系统的情况下
That's the idea, yes.I mean, we wouldn't
be able to repair them completely,
我们不能完全修好它们
但是我们绝对可以打几个补丁
not without landing and shutting down and
such, but we can definitely patch them up.
Zelanka和他的小队正在以
最快的速度工作
Look, Zelenka and his team are
working as fast as they possibly can.
但是我们还在流失大量的能量
The problem is we're still leaking a lot of power.
即使我们已经减少了这么多消耗?
Even with all our reductions?
恐怕 是的
I'm afraid so, yes.
看 这事这座城市进入超空间所需的
最少能量
Look, this is the minimum amount of power the
city requires to execute a jump into hyperspace.
如果我们不在一小时之内修补好
管线 它就会低于这个水平了
If we don't fix the power conduits inside
of an hour, we'll drop below that level.
如果那样 我们就只有坐以待毙
After that, we're stuck.
距护盾失效大概还有30小时
然后我们就会在真空中死去
We'll have maybe 30 hours before the shields
fail, and we all die in the vacuum of space.
- 你没事吧?
- 我没事
- You okay?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
- 他们把玻璃都清除了
- 好的
- They got all the glass out.
- Good.
你需要我帮忙?
You need me somewhere?
我需要你在这好好养伤
Right here getting better.
没事的 我可以走了
All right, well, I'm good to go.
中校...
Colonel...
她没事吧?
she okay?
她还活着 但是状况很糟
She's alive, but she's in bad shape.
她断了6根肋骨
其中一根还穿通了肺
She's got six broken ribs,
one of which punctured a lung.
不过她没有任何脊髓损伤
Amazingly, she doesn't
have any spinal damage,
但是她的头部被撞得很严重
but her head got knocked
around pretty good.
她正在遭受脑水肿的煎熬
那可能造成严重的大脑损伤
She's suffering from cerebral oedema, which
may have caused substantial brain damage,
什么意思?
what does that all mean?
现在说还太早 但是...
Well, it's too early
to know for sure, but...
如果她活下来
我是说"如果"...
if she survives, and I
got to stress the "if"...
她再也不会是原来的Elizabeth
she'll never be the
same Elizabeth again.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我得去拿点东西 然后到手术室
I've got to get some things
and get back in there.
我们人手不足
绝大多数的人员在Apollo上
We're understaffed. Most of
our team's on the Apollo.
这边进行的怎么样?
How's it going on this end?
事实上 惊人的好
Actually, you know, remarkably well.
- 真的?
- 没错
- Really?
- Yes, yes, yes.
拆解备用导管的部件和控制水晶...
Cannibalizing parts and
crystals from secondary conduits
然后接入到主导管上
and interfacing them with
the primary ones is...
这工作进行的十分顺利
is going very smoothly.
好的 如果我们保持目前的速度
Yes, if we keep our current pace,
我们应该可以在能量低于必须值前
we should be done well before we drop
below the necessary power requirements to,
进入超空间并和Apollo会合
you know, jump into hyperspace
and meet up with the Apollo.
- 这太好了
- 是的 我就知道你会很高兴
- Well, that's fantastic.
- Yes.Yeah, I thought you'd be happy.
高兴?
Happy?
真的有机会让我们渡过这件事
我是欣喜若狂
There's actually a chance we might make
it through this thing. I am ecstatic.
我得去做一点...
I am going to
do a little--
Sheppard中校 Mckay博士
请马上到控制室!
Colonel Sheppard, Dr.McKay, please
report to the control room immediately!
那只持续了... 一秒钟?
That lasted what, like, a second?
你们得看看这个
You're going to want to look at this.
- 那是什么?
- 小行星带?!
What is that? An asteroid belt?
亚光速引擎还没有上线吗?
Are the sub-lights
still off-line?
没有
Yup.
你得扩张护盾了
We're going to need
to expand the shields.
我们没有足够的能量
We don't have enough power.
我们要多久才能到那?
要多久才能穿过?
How long till we get there, and
how long till we get through it?
大约10分钟到达 然后也许2分钟穿过
About 10 minutes until we get there. After
that, maybe two minutes to get through.
两分钟就能通过一个小行星区域?
Two minutes to get
through an asteroid field?
我们不是完全通过
Well, we're not passing
all the way through.
只是蹭一下边缘
We're just going to skim the edge.
你连两分钟的护盾都不能给我?
You can't even give me two
minutes of full shields?
我和你一样想把护盾打开
但是我们承受不起能量消耗
I'd like them up as much as you would,
but we just can't afford the power.
Rodney
Rodney--
Zelanka需要45分钟来完成
能量管线的修复
Look, Zelenka needs 45 minutes to
complete the repairs to the power conduits.
即使我们只开1分钟护盾
就能消耗光他全部的时间
If we raise the shields even for one minute,
it'll eat up all his time. We can't do it.
好吧
Okay.
他们有多大?
How big are they?
我们现在在一个很大的太阳系里
Well, we're in the middle of a
pretty big solar system right now,
小行星带可能是以前行星的残骸...
and the asteroid belt's probably made
up of remnants of early failed planets,
那么 你知道...
so, you know...
有楼房那么大 或者更大
building-size and larger.
我可以做到椅子上
用Drone清开一条道路
I could get in the chair, fire drones,
and clear a path to travel through.
好主意 但是放椅子的房间现在在
护盾外面
In principle a good idea, but the chair room's
outside of the shield right now,
我们永远不可能过去
and we'd never get to it.
我们可以...
Look we could, um...
不 这个不行...
no, that's not going to work.
我们可以...
Uh, we could...
在底部的人有多少有古人基因?
how many people on the
base have the ancient gene?
20左右 不 不 这不是一个好主意
20 or so.Look, no, no. No,
no, no, that is a bad idea--
- 你有更好的吗?
- 是的
- Uou have a better idea?
- Yes.
我会的 我只是...
只是需要更多时间
I can.I just--
I need some time.
联系底部所有有古人基因的人
Contact everyone on the base
who has the ancient gene,
叫他们在Jumper bay见我
tell them to meet me
up at the jumper bay.
好吧 快办
Well, do it.
这就是说我们不能开启护盾
因为我们没有足够的能量
Which means we can't raise the shields
because we don't have enough power.
如果我们不为这座城清开一条道路
它会被撞碎
If we don't clear a path for
the city, it'll get ripped apart.
我们得开上我们有的全部Jumper
So, we're going to take
every last jumper we have,
然后用Drone为这座城
开出一条路...
and we're going to clear a path
through the belt by firing our drones.
对不起
Excuse me.
Jumper我只开过两次
I've really only flown a jumper twice,
而且我从未用过Drone 那...
and I've never actually
fired a live drone, so--
你在模拟里试过 不是吗?
you've done it in simulations, right?
是的 但是...
Well, yeah, but--
它们基本上是一样的
It's basically the same thing.
如果McKay能搞定 你也可以
If McKay can do it, you can do it.
没错 关于这个 我...
Yes, about that,
actually, I--
听着 我知道那很危险
Look, I know it's dangerous.
我知道你们很多人
没在这些事上花很多时间
I know a lot of you haven't logged
a lot of hours in these things,
但是现在这是我们唯一的选择
but right now, it's the only
viable option we have, or, um...
要不然就只有等死了
Or die.
我们行动吧
Let's get moving.
好的 我为你们载入了航行信息
All right, I've loaded a
flight formation for all of you.
沿着你们的预定目标
干掉你们航线上的一切障碍
Stay in your designated positions,
take out anything that's in your path.
Drone都已经装满
所以弹药应该不是问题
You've got a full load of drones,
so ammo shouldn't be a problem.
看上去像老的视频游戏 Asteroids
Looks like the old
video game, Asteroids.
随你怎么搞
Whatever works for you.
我 Asteroids 玩得很差
I was terrible at Asteroids.
我想我有一次得了0分
I think I actually scored zero once.
那么只有一条路走了--向上
Then there's only one
way to go, and that's up.
好了 大伙 我们走
All right, everyone. Let's go.
打开Jumper Bay舱门
Open the jumper bay doors.
快点 伙计们 保持队形
Come on, guys, stay in formation.
我们不能留出任何空隙
We can't afford any gaps.
没错 就是这样
看见了 不是很难
Yeah, there you go.
See? Not so hard.
Jumper们 你们应该在3秒内到达
Jumpers, you should
be in range in three...
2...
two...
1...
one.
随便开火
Fire at will.
打的漂亮 伙计们
Nice shooting, people.
它们的数量太多 速度太快
我们不能全部都打中
There's too many of them and they're coming
in too fast.We're not going to get them all.
加强火力 一次发射4个
Double up, fire four a-piece.
我一次控制不了4枚Drone
I can't control four
drones at the same time.
集中注意力
Just concentrate.
该死!
Damm it!
别担心 你说的没错
Don't worry about it.You were right.
我们没法在第一次穿越的时候
就全部搞定
We can't get everything
on the first pass.
他们有清除足够的小行星吗?
Have they destroyed enough
asteroids to clear a path?
我们就快知道了!
(中国人! 中国人!!)
We're about to find out.
那么 现在做什么?
Well, now what?
按我的指令 Bolton和Levine...
Well,on my mark,you,bolton,and levine
将离开队形掉头回城
are going to break formation
and head back to the city.
打掉我们错过的东西
Take out anything that we missed.
哦 那听上去很重要
也许别人应该去...
Oh, that sounds important.
Maybe someone else should--
脱离!
Break!
McKay...
你左边有一个打的
you've a big one on your left.
- 我看见了
- 10秒内冲撞
- I see it.
- Impact in 10 seconds.
那是什么?
What was that?
小碎片正在通过
Smaller pieces getting through.
其中一些明显不够小
Some of them evidently not so small.
现在破怀被限制在城市边缘
Right now damage is confined
to the outer edge of the city.
希望它保持这样
Let's hope it stays that way.
好了 我们通过了
All right, we're through.
我们现在回头 带上掉队的人
Now we're going to double
back, pick up any stragglers.
好了
That's it.
我们成功了
We made it.
我不敢相信这真的成功了
真是太惊人了
I can't believe that actually
worked. That was amazing.
你干得很不错 Rodney
You did good, Rodney.
Zelenka现在应该修好导管了
Zelenka and his team should
have the conduits repaired now,
那么我想我们终于可以脱身了
so I think we're
finally out of the woods.
Sheppard中校 McKay博士
请立即到控制室
Colonel Sheppard, Dr.McKay, please
report to the control room immediately.
啊 拜托!
Aw, come on!
发生了什么?
What the hell happened?
超空间引擎离线了
The hyperdrive is offline.
我以为它是好的
I thought it was good to go.
原来是 但是有几块大石头
撞击了城市
It was, but a few large pieces
of rock impacted the city,
有一个控制阵列损坏了
and one of the control
arrays was damaged.
在我们修好之前 我们不能跳跃
We can't jump until we fix it.
我告诉过你我对付小行星不行
I told you I was no good at Asteroids.
损坏的管线在城市的外围
The damaged conduits are on
the outer edge of the city,
很遗憾 那里不在护盾的保护之内
which, sadly, is outside of
the protection of the shield.
我们可以用传送机尽可能的靠近
We can use the transporters
to get us very close,
但是还是需要太空行走的
but it will still require a space walk.
这也不是很糟糕
That shouldn't be too bad.
如果不是那些微行星
这就是小菜一碟
It'll be a breeze, with the
exception of the micro-asteroids.
什么东西?
The what?
我们刚刚通过一个小行星带
We just came through an asteroid belt.
主要的部分在我们的后面 但是
还有一些子弹大的小石头在前面
The big stuff's behind is, but there's a
bunch of little bullet-sized rocks out there.
小石子弹
Tiny rock bullets.
太好了
Great.
我确定你们会没事的
I'm sure you'll be fine.
那么 你为什么不去?
Well, then why aren't you going?
因为你已经研究出详细的修复方法了
Well, because you've already worked
out the details of the repair.
如果你要再教我 那就是浪费时间
You know it will be a waste
of time getting me up to speed.
说道时间 我们还有多少?
Speaking of time, how much do we have?
你们穿好宇航服以后 15分钟
Well, once you're suited
up, uh...15 minutes?
就这么多?
That's it, huh?
嘿 如果不是我们没有对管线的
修复减慢了能量流失
Hey, if the patch-job we did on the
conduits hadn't slowed down the power loss,
我们早就到死亡线了
we'd have hit the deadline already.
你们可以搞定的
You can do this.
好的
Right.
Mckay! 我一直在找你
McKay! I've been trying to reach you.
你知道 我再拯救城市等等
Elizabeth怎么样了?
Well, you know, trying to save the
city and whatnot. Look, how's elizabeth?
这就是我要和你谈的 她很不好
I need to talk to you. She's really bad.
实际上 她伤的太重
我们已经无能为力了
She's so far gone, I don't think
there's anything we can do to heal her.
我的天 你确定吗?
Oh, my god. Are you sure?
我用尽了所有的医学方法
但是没有一个有效
I've exhausted every medical
possibility, and none of it's worked.
她  她会死吗?
She... she's going to die?
我还有一个想法
但是我需要你的帮助
Well, I do have one more
idea, but I need your help.
我? 你要我干什么?
Me? What do you need me for?
看见这些了吗?
See those?
他们是什么?
What are they?
记得Weir博士被复制者攻击的时候
他使她感染了...
Remember when Dr.Weir was attacked by
that replicator, and he infected her--
纳米机器人
Nanites.
Carson用电磁脉冲使它们失效了
Carson was able to render them inert
using an electro-magnetic pulse.
但是它们还在她的身体里
But they're still in her system.
你真是个天才
You're a genius.
我就是想拯救一条生命
Well, you know, trying to
save a life and whatnot.
你要什么?
You want to what?
重新激活Wier身上的纳米机器人
Reactivate Weir's nanites.
那是个很恐怖很恐怖的主意
That is a terrible, terrible idea.
什么? 我会重新编程的
What? I'd reprogram them.
不要
No.
John 我们快要失去她了
John, we are losing her here.
Keller和她的小队已经竭尽全力了
Keller and her team have
done everything they can.
如果我能重新编程这些机器人
让他们修复她的身体...
If I can reprogram the nanites to help repair her body
without trying to take over her brain then--
好大一个"如果" 不是吗?
Well, that's a big "if", isn't it?
我很确信我能重新编程
以达到我们的目的
I'm fairly confident I can reprogram
them to do only what we want.
"很确信"?
"Fairly confident?"
如果它们恢复了并且
和其他复制者通讯 怎么办?
What if they come back online and start
communicating with the other replicators?
我们现在最不需要的就是一堆
机器战舰出现
The last thing we need right now is
a bunch of robot warships showing up.
你在听吗?
Are you listening?
听着 我说了 我可以让他们
变得完全无害
Look, I said I can reprogram
them to be completely harmless.
在你确定之前
我不会再继续这个谈话
I am not having this
conversation until you're sure.
我和别人一样想救活Elizabeth
I want to save Elizabeth
as much as anyone,
但是她不会想让我们置这座城
于险境 即使是为了救她自己
but she wouldn't want us risking
the city, not even for her.
顺便说一下 你的决定是对的
That was the right call, by the way.
希望如此
Yeah, let's hope so.
Apollo有来消息吗?
Any word from the Apollo?
没 还没有
No, not yet.
你在干什么?
What you working on?
我正尝试找一个方法
找到或者联系Atlantis
I'm actually trying to figure out
a way to find or contact Atlantis.
他们明显偏离航向了 不是吗?
Well...they've obviously
veered off course, right?
上一次有人用Atlantis的
超空间引擎是什么时候?
Like, when was the last time
Atlantis' hyperdrives were used?
一百万年前?
Like, a million years ago?
我是说 谁知道这样的闲置会
造成什么样的影响?
I mean, who knows what that kind of
inactivity could have done to them.
我想 他们更有可能是脱离
超空间过早了
I think it's more likely that they
jumped out of hyperspace too soon.
他们只有一个ZPM来飞行
They were only flying with one ZPM.
也许McKay低估了飞行所需的能量
Maybe McKay under-estimated
the power requirements.
Mckay? 啊!
McKay? Ah...
不管怎么样 我知道怎么找到他们
Either way, I know how to find them.
真的?
Really?
没错 我们做一个AGB
全星门广播
Yeah, we do an A.G.B.,
An all gates bulletin.
这有点像一个全面通缉(APB)
只是使用了星门
It's like an all points
bulletin, only with stargates.
- 哦 好了...
- 不 是真的
- Oh, come on.
- No, no, really.
我们写一个程序同时
拨打飞马系里所有的星门
We'll create a program, we'll dial all
the gates in the Pegasus Galaxy at once,
然后尝试同Atlantis建立无线电联系
and try to establish radio
contact with Atlantis.
但是Atlantis的星门还不在系统内
But the Atlantis gate is off the grid.
没错 但是如果他们和另一个星门
靠的足够近...
Right, but if they're
close to another gate--
那么他们现在就应该联系上我们了
then they would have
contacted us by now.
没错
Yeah.
那么 你想到了什么?
So, uh, what have you come up with then?
还没有 但是...
Well, nothing yet, but--
至少我在尝试了
well, at least I am trying.
我在想点子 我...
I'm generating ideas here. I...
对不起
Sorry.
我事实上很惊讶
I'm actually surprised.
这各区域的损伤看上去很小
The damage in this area
seems to be quite minimal.
我猜正好相反
I beg to differ.
哦 我的天
Oh, my.
让我猜
Let me guess..
控制阵列在那边
the array is over there.
恐怕是的
I'm afraid so.
太好了
Great.
那该死的是什么?
What the hell was that?
微行星
Micro-asteroid.
好的...
Right...
好
All right.
看上去我们得跳过去
Looks like we're going to have to jump.
但我跳不了100英尺(300米)
But I can't jump 100 feet.
我们在宇宙空间 记得吗?
We're in space, remember?
这不算太远
It's not that far a distance.
我要这个绳索拴住你
Look, I'm going to hook you
up with this tether, okay?
然后我解除你靴子的磁力
Then I'm going to
demagnetize your boots.
- 然后我把你扔出去
- 等等 什么?
- Then I'm going to throw you.
- Wait, what? What?
然后我在绳索拉紧之前
解除我靴子的磁力
Then I'm going to demag my
boots before the tether catches.
你的惯性应该会把我们两个
都拉到走廊的洞里
Your inertia should pull both of us
over the hole and onto the hallway.
这会很简单的
It'll be a cinch.
但是如果你弄偏了怎么办?
But what if you miss?
你只能相信我了 博士
You're just going to
have to trust me, Doc.
相信我至少可以扔得动你
Trust me as far as I
can throw you, actually.
- 很好笑
- 好吧 我们干吧
- Very funny.
- All right, let's do this.
那... 太不可置信了
That was... was unbelievable.
开始工作吧
Let's get to work.
好的
All right.
进行的如何?
How's it going?
很慢
Slowly.
你有找到安全激活这些纳米机器
的方法吗?
Have you found a way to
reactivate the nanites safely?
- 简单点说 是的 复杂点说 没有
- 什么?
- Short story, yes.Long story, no.
- What?
我百分之百确定我可以激活它们
I'm 100% certain that I
can reactivate the nanites
而且让它们帮助Elizabeth恢复
and have them help put
Elizabeth back together.
好的...
Okay...
问题是它们会用复制出来的机器
替换损坏的细胞
The problem is, that they would do it by replacing
her damaged cells with replicated nanites,
那么一旦我让他们关闭...
so the moment I tell
them to turn inert again--
这些细胞会停止工作
然后她会死
those cells would stop
functioning, and she'd die.
是的
Yeah.
好消息是我可以让他们...
Well, the good news is, I've been
able to program them in such a way
不会伤害她 这一点我很确定
that they would never
harm her, I'm sure of that.
而且我已经关闭了它们的
次空间通讯能力
Plus, I've shut down their ability to
contact the replicators via subspace,
那么她和我们都会很安全
但是她下半辈子就会成为半复制者
so both she and we would be safe, but she'd
be part replicator for the rest of her life.
Sheppard肯定不希望这样
Yeah, Sheppard's not
going to go for that.
也许我可以让它们修复她自身的有机细胞
There's a slight possibility I might be able
to make them help repair her organic cells,
然后在完成之后关掉它们...
and then shut down when
they're done, but...
可我需要更多的时间
I'm going to need more time.
好吧 交给你了 祝好运!
Okay, well, I'll leave
you to it then. Good luck.
谢了
Mm, thanks.
抱歉 我可能需要更多时间
I'm sorry.It's taking
longer than I expected.
手套妨碍了速度
These gloves are making
the work so much slower.
别担心
Don't worry about it.
还剩四分钟我们的能量就不足以
跳入超空间了
We've still got four minutes before the
energy dips too low and we can't make the jump.
所以 也不要有太大压力
So, no pressure then.
Radek!
听我说 他们...
Listen, they, uh...
他们说你听不到我说话 可我...
they say you can't
hear me, but I just...
我只想...
I just wanted to, um...
只想说谢谢你
I just wanted to thank you.
谢谢你...
Thanks for letting me...
两年前接纳了我
stay here a couple of years ago.
因为我不知道还能不能...
Because I don't know if
I would still be, um...
谢谢你 Weir博士
Thank you, dr.Weir.
我做错什么了?
What did I do?
没什么 不是你的原因
不过你得离开一下
Nothing, it wasn't you,
but you need to leave.
再挂一袋甘露醇
Hang another bag of manitol.
你被一块小殒石击中了 疼不疼?
You've been hit by a
micro-asteroid. Does it hurt?
不疼
It doesn't.
你在发抖
You're in shock.
我的太空服破了一个洞
There's a hole in my suit.
没关系 我调节了一下上面的按钮
用来增加压力
It's okay. I've dialed up controls
to create positive pressure.
我去叫一艘Jumper飞船
必须马上送你去手术室
I'm calling a jumper. I've
got to get you to the O.R.
我们现在不能走
We can't leave yet.
我必须完成修复工作
I have to finish the repairs.
告诉我怎么做就行了
Just tell me what to do.
这太复杂了
It's too complicated.
我已经快完成了
I'm almost finished.
帮帮忙 帮我转过身去
Please, help me turn around.
Mckay博士?
Dr. McKay?
什么事 Keller?
What is it, Keller?
Elizabeth快要不行了
如果我们再不开始 可能就没机会了
Elizabeth is crashing. If we're going
to do this thing, we need to do it now.
我还需要些时间
I need more time.
我们没有时间了
We don't have more time.
我没法维持她的血压
如果她的颅压还在继续升高
I can't keep her blood pressure up,
and if her ICP continues to climb,
就没办法挽救了
there's no bringing her back.
好吧 我现在就把程序传给你
Okay, I'm transferring
the program to you now.
我这就过来
I'm on my way.
如果他们的确是过早脱离超空间
那么最简单的方法就是
You know, the easiest thing to do if they
really did fall out of hyperspace early
沿着去往M12-578的路线原路返回
is to fly back over the path
between M12-578 and Atlantis.
可这要花费上百万年
Well, that would take
over a million years.
这也就是我们使用超空间的原因
That's why we have hyperspace.
我们可以使用Apollo号上的
远程探测器
We could use the Apollo's
long-range sensors.
可那些远程探测器
不能在超空间中工作
Those long-range sensors,
they don't work in hyperspace.
这我知道 可我们可以在超空间中
跳跃一小段  然后出来看看
I know, but we could make
a little jump, look around,
然后再跳一小段 再出来看看...
make another little
jump, look around, and...
直到找到他们
until we find them.
这个办法好
Yeah, that's good.
好吧 如果合理的安排跳跃
我们需要跳跃...
Uh, so using those sensors,
conservatively, we'd have to make...
180,000次
180,000 little jumps.
这需要好几年
It'd take a few years.
除非他们大幅增加
远程探测器的探测距离
Unless they seriously augment
the long-range sensors.
好啊 可谁能办到呢?
Oh, yeah, who's going to do that?
他们的飞船上又没有Asgard
It's not like they
have an Asgard on board.
去一趟飞马星系如何?
Feel like taking a little
trip to the Pegasus Galaxy?
还剩最后几个调整
Just some final adjustments.
你干得很棒 Radek
You're doing a great job, Radek.
我已经叫了一艘Jumper
I've called a jumper.
好了 完成了
There. I'm done.
控制室 我是Sheppard
Control room, this is Sheppard.
等我们回到护盾区域之后
马上进行超空间跳跃
As soon as we get inside the
shield, activate the hyperspace jump.
抱歉 John 我们办不到
I'm sorry, John, but we can't.
为什么? Zelenka已经修好了
Why not? Zelenka just finished repairs.
是的 这我知道
可我们的能量刚刚跌入警戒线以下
Yes, I know, but we've
just dropped below the line.
没有足够的能量了
We don't have enough power.
他没什么事吧?
Is she going to be okay?
我想是的 还好没有击中大动脉
I think so. It didn't
hit any major arteries.
真走运
Lucky.
我可不这么认为 现在他跟我们一样
被困在这里了
I wouldn't say that. He's still
stuck here just like the rest of us.
是啊
So it's true.
终于修复了超空间引擎
可我们又没有足够的能量发动
Finally fixed the hyperdrive, now we
don't have enough juice to go anywhere.
在护盾失效之前 我们还有28个小时
We've only got 28 hours
before the shields fail.
有什么计划?
So, what's the plan?
不知道 我要去找Mckay
I don't know, I got to find McKay.
他来了
He's in there.
什么?
What?
嘿!
Hey!
我听说了 我们没有及时修好阵列
I heard we didn't get
the array fixed in time.
你刚才在干什么?
What were you doing in there?
听着 她就要死了 知道么?
Look, she was dying, okay?
Rodney...
她的心脏快不行了
神经系统也濒临崩溃
look, her heart was weak,
her nervous system was fried.
你干什么了?
What did you do?
我重新激活了那些纳米机器人
I reactivated the nanites.
真该死 Mckay!
Damn it, McKay!
你当时很忙! 在这生死攸关的时刻
如果我不采取行动的话...
Look, you were busy! It was
life or death. If I didn't act--
是的  她会死的 我知道!
Yes, she would have died, I know!
我知道你在想什么 可是救了Elizabeth
并不一定就等于将我们置于危险境地
Okay, I know what you're thinking, but
helping Elizabeth is not putting us at risk.
你刚刚激活了复制者的纳米病毒
You just reactivated
the replicator nanites.
它们是无害的
They're harmless.
我可以百分之百肯定 它们不会控制她
并跟其他复制者联系!
Look, I am 100% certain they're not going to
try to take her over her, or contact the others!
不 不 你永远都不能肯定
No, no, you can't know that for sure.
不 我可以
Yes. Yes, I can.
关掉它们
Shut it down.
可...这会害死她
But...that would kill her.
如果是Elizabeth 她会怎样做?
你认为她愿意看到这种结局?
What would Elizabeth want?
Do you think she'd want this?
是的 她肯定会跟你一样
Yes. She'd sure as hell
do the same for you.
那很显然 你还不是很了解她
Then you obviously
didn't know her very well.
好吧 也许吧 再等些时候
你自己去问她吧...
Well, maybe not, but you know what, give
it some time, you can ask her, herself--
不行! 这样太危险了
立刻把它们关掉
No! It's too dangerous.
Shut it down right now.
不 我不去
No. No, I'm not going to.
Meyers...
拿一台EMP(电磁脉冲)发生器到手术室来
bring an EMP generator to the O.R.
你能不能听我一句话?
Would you please just listen to me?
Keller医生!
Dr. Keller!
John...
Rodney...
发生什么了?
What's going on?
没必要进行隔离
The quarantine is unnecessary.
如果发生意外 我看你怎么交待
Well, you'll excuse me if
I wait for a second opinion.
这太荒谬了
Okay, this is stupid.
- 什么?
- 我们之间吵架
- What is?
- Us fighting.
我知道你对我有些不满
也许你有一些借口
Look, I know you're not happy with
me, and you may have some cause.
可不管怎么样 如果我们想不出
一个脱身的办法 这又有什么用呢?
Anyway, it's not going to matter much if
we don't figure a way out of this, right?
我们必须相互协作 所以...
Look, we have to work together, so...
我...我很抱歉
so, so I'm...I'm sorry.
接受你的道歉
Apology accepted.
好吧
All right.
该有人去跟她说说话
Well, someone should talk to her.
Teyla在里面
Well, Teyla's in there.
好的
All right.
他们不该这样做的
They shouldn't have done this.
我们都不想失去你 Elizabeth
None of us wanted to
lose you, Elizabeth.
可要是那些纳米机器人
联络其他复制者呢?
And what happens if the nanites are
able to contact the other replicators?
Rodney相信这是不可能的
Rodney does not believe
that is possible.
不行 不值得冒这个险
No, it's reckless.
照我来看...
In my opinion...
很值得冒这个险
it is well worth the risk.
你根本不知道我上次经历了什么
You have no idea what I
went through the last time.
相信我
Believe me...
这是个很糟糕的主意
this is a very bad idea.
你们在这里干什么?
What the hell are you doing up here?
总比在医务室无聊的等死强吧?
Well, there's not much point sitting in
the infirmary waiting to die, is there?
好吧 现在是什么状况?
All right, where do we stand?
次空间通讯我们是不用考虑了
Well, we can pretty much forget
about subspace communications.
主控制阵列差不多完全被光束摧毁了
The main control array was almost
completely damaged by the beam.
不过 我还有一个主意
I do, however, have another idea.
说说看
Let's hear it.
我们之所以不能利用剩余的能量
跃入超空间
Well, the reason why
we cannot use the power
是因为城市不让我们这样干
we have left to execute a short jump into
hyperspace is that the city will not let us.
这是一个安全措施
不过我有办法绕开它
It's a safety protocol, but
I might be able to bypass it.
然后呢 有什么好处?
What does that give us?
不是很好
Not much.
是的 我们还是无法跟Apollo回合
Well, we wouldn't be
able to get to the Apollo,
无法到达最近的星门
and we wouldn't be able to
get to the nearest stargate,
不过也许我们可以在附近
找到一个适于居住的星球
but we might be able to find a
habitable planet within range.
我现在已经派人
去用探测器进行扫描了
I have my team running
sensor sweeps right now.
他没有讲那个安全措施
He's conveniently leaving out the reason
不让我们这样干的原因
why those safety protocols are
in place in the first place.
好吧 如果能量不足
Yes, well, with insufficient power,
那么城市在进入超空间之前
就有可能被撕裂
there is a chance that the city could be ripped
apart as we try to enter the hyperspace window.
几率有多大?
What kind of chance?
50%
50-50.
那我得说 Radek 这不是个好点子
Well, I got to tell you,
Radek, I'm not loving that idea.
那艘试验Jumper
Experimental jumper.
还记得不 几个月前
我被那台机器打中 然后就...
Remember when I was zapped by that
machine a few months ago, and I got...
一下子变得聪明多了?
well, even smarter than I normally am?
差点害死你的那次? 记得
The one that almost killed you? Yeah.
在我恢复原形之前
Well, before I was reset,
我已经完成给一艘Puddle Jumper
装上超空间引擎了
I was very close to giving one of
our puddle jumpers a hyperdrive.
- 你能完成么?
- 当然
- Can you finish it?
- Yeah.
也许吧
Yes, I probably can.
那我们可以飞到Appolo那里
告诉我们现在的位置
All right, great. We'll make a jump
to the Apollo, tell them where we are.
- 不行
- 为什么?
- No.
- Why no?
Jumper上的超空间引擎能力有限
The jumper's hyperdrive
would be limited.
没法飞那么远
Wae wouldn't be able to jump that far.
那可以飞多远?
How far then?
你觉得呢 大概是 二?
What do you think, like, two?
大概吧?
Yeah. Two and change maybe?
保守估计 大概有两千光年
Conservatively, maybe 2000 light years.
这是在此范围内的星门地址
This is a list of addresses
that are within range.
那我们多飞几次 把队员们都
转送到其中的一颗星球上
All right, we'll make a bunch of trips
and ferry the crew to one of the planets.
这个也不行
Again, no.
为什么?
Why not?
那个引擎从来没有测试过
Well, the drive's never been tested.
幸运的话 可以飞个一两次
Yeah, we'd be lucky if we get two jumps.
这样可以到某地飞一个来回
We'll make a return trip somewhere.
是的 理想的话 还可以找到几个ZPM
Yeah, ideally, somewhere
with a few ZPMs to spare.
给Atlantis提供能量
We come back, we get
atlantis fully powered.
那就太好了
Yeah, that'd be great.
M7R-227
M7r-227.
那是什么?
What's that?
这个...
Well...
那里有ZPM?
there's a planet out there with ZPMs?
是的 我们知道他们有几个ZPM
Yeah... yeah, we know
they have a few ZPMs.
那是哪里?
And who would that be?
那儿? 那儿是复制者的母星
That? That would be the
replicator homeworld.
敢去么?
You feel up to a heist?